Dorothy Kenyon Papers, 1850-1998
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS (1923-1971)
  - Voluntary Organizations and a World Without War Conference: correspondence, 1964 (Box 61, Folder 8)
  - West Side Community Conference: correspondence, 1966 (Box 61, Folder 9)
  - Western College for Women: clipping, newsletter, and program, 1966 (Box 61, Folder 10)
  - Woman's Forum: pamphlets and programs, 1946, 1952 (Box 61, Folder 11)
  - Woman's Rights Centennial: program, 1948 (Box 61, Folder 12)
  - Women in World Affairs: correspondence, invitations, lists of delegates and attendees, programs, publicity, and seating chart, [see OVERSIZED MATERIAL], 1953-54 (Box 61, Folder 13)
  - Women's American ORT: program, 1945 (Box 61, Folder 14)
  - Women's Bar Association: correspondence, 1971 (Box 61, Folder 15)
  - Women's City Club of Cleveland: correspondence, 1948 (Box 61, Folder 16)
  - Women's City Club of New York, Inc.: correspondence, newsletters, and programs, 1949-70 (Box 61, Folder 17)
  - Women's Conference Group: correspondence and publicity, 1949, 1966 (Box 61, Folder 18)
  - Women's International League for Peace and Freedom: correspondence and publicity, 1947, 1960 (Box 61, Folder 19)
  - Women's Medical College of Pennsylvania: clippings, correspondence, invitations, newsletters, and programs, 1953-1971, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 20)
  - Women's Organization for World Order: program, 1936 (Box 61, Folder 21)
  - Women's Strike Coalition: correspondence (includes Betty Friedan), programs, and publicity, 1970-71 (Box 61, Folder 22)
  - Women's Strike for Equality: correspondence (includes Gloria Steinem), and publicity, 1970 (Box 61, Folder 23)
  - Women's Trade Union League: agenda and program, 1949-50 (Box 61, Folder 24)
  - Women's University Club: correspondence and invitations, 1951-62 (Box 61, Folder 25)
  - Workers Defense League: correspondence and invitations, 1949-71 (Box 61, Folder 26)
  - Workman's Circle: correspondence and newsletter, 1964 (Box 61, Folder 27)
  - YWCA: clippings, correspondence, invitations, minutes, and publicity, 1949-66 (Box 61, Folder 28)
  - Youth Board Urban Residence: correspondence and printed material, 1967-68 (Box 61, Folder 29)
- SERIES VII. SUBJECTS (1925-1971)
  - Abortion: clippings and printed material, 1968-71, [see also SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS] (Box 61, Folder 30)
  - Anti-communism: clippings, 1948-62,n.d. (Box 61, Folder 31)
  - Civil rights: clippings and printed material, 1958-68, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 32)
  - Conscription of women: notes and printed material, 1943, n.d. (Box 61, Folder 33)
  - Displaced persons: printed material, 1943 (Box 61, Folder 34)
  - Equal Employment Opportunity Commission: printed material, reports, and correspondence, 1966-67 (Box 62, Folder 1)
  - Equal pay bill: correspondence and printed material, 1943-44 (Box 62, Folder 2)
  - ERA: memoranda, correspondence, and printed material, 1938-70, n.d., [see also SERIES IV. SPEECHES AND WRITINGS] (Box 62, Folder 3)
  - Eugenics: printed material, 1933-38 (Box 62, Folder 4)
  - Feminism: clippings, newsletters, and leaflets, 1966-71, [see also SERIES IV. SPEECHES AND WRITINGS and SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS] (Box 62, Folder 5)
  - International politics: clippings, 1940-60, [see also SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS] (Box 62, Folder 6)
  - Jury service for women: clipping, 1935, [see also SERIES V. LEGAL PRACTICE] (Box 62, Folder 7)
  - Kennedy, Robert F. Memorial Meeting: program and correspondence, 1963 (Box 62, Folder 8)
  - Legal system: clippings, 1938-46 (Box 62, Folder 9)
  - New York public transportation: clipping, 1947 (Box 62, Folder 10)
  - Nixon, Richard M: clipping, 1956 (Box 62, Folder 11)
  - Pitkin, Winifred: printed material, 1960, [see also SERIES III. CORRESPONDENCE and SERIES VIII. PHOTOGRAPHS] (Box 62, Folder 12)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D. Memorial Meeting: invitation, 1945 (Box 62, Folder 13)
  - Status of women, international: clippings and printed material, 1945-60, [see also SERIES IV. SPEECHES AND WRITINGS, SERIES V. LEGAL PRACTICE, and SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS] (Box 62, Folder 14)
  - Strauss, Dorothy S.: clipping, 1960 (Box 62, Folder 15)
  - Sumner, Jessie: clipping, 1944 (Box 62, Folder 16)
  - Supreme Court of U.S.: clippings, printed material, 1959-62, [see also SERIES IV. LEGAL PRACTICE] (Box 62, Folder 17)
  - Vietnam: correspondence, 1965-66 (Box 62, Folder 18)
  - Working women: notes, printed material, 1939-46 (Box 62, Folder 19)
- SERIES VIII. PHOTOGRAPHS (1888-1971)
  - Personal, 1888-1910
    - Kenyon at about age 5, circa 1893 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Kenyon at about age 7, circa 1895 (Box 63)
    - Kenyon with William, Minnie, and Theodore Kenyon, mid 1880s (Box 63)
    - Kenyon and parents William and Minnie Kenyon, circa 1888 (Box 63)
    - Kenyon and Ruth Wilby, circa 1888 (Box 63, Folder 1)
    - Houston Kenyon's "sambo" doll in New York City, circa 1890s (Box 63)
    - Kenyon with Minnie and Theodore Kenyon, circa 1890s (Box 63)
    - Kenyon with William and Minnie Kenyon; Katherine, Eleanor, Louise and Ruth Wilby; Grandmother Kenyon, and Houston Kenyon, circa 1890s (Box 63)
    - Robert Kenyon, Mr. and Mrs. Alan Kenyon, Sue (Sawyer?), William and Mary Kenyon, Theodore Kenyon, Robert Kenyon, Sr., Douglas and Ross Kenyon, 1900 (Box 63)
    - Kenyon at age 13, 1901 (Box 63)
    - Kenyon, Theodore, and Houston, 1901 (Box 63)
    - Kenyon with Maria Stanwood and Houston Kenyon, circa 1905 (Box 63)
    - Kenyon with William and Houston Kenyon, 1906 (Box 63)
    - Kenyon with William Kenyon at Smith College, 1906 (Box 63)
    - Kenyon with Smith classmates in New York City (3 photos), 1906-08 (Box 63)
    - Kenyon with Katherine Wilby Berna, William and Minnie Kenyon, and Mary Berna, 1907 (Box 63)
    - Houston Kenyon's 10th birthday party, 1910 (Box 63)
    - Photograph of portrait of Kenyon as a girl, n.d. (Box 63)
    - Kenyon with Mary Townley, Susan Sanger, Rebecca, Robert, William, Mary, and Allen Kenyon, n.d. (Box 63)
    - Kenyon and Houston in New York, n.d. (Box 63)
  - Personal, 1880-1910, n.d. (larger prints)
    - Editorial board of Horace Mann School literary magazine The Manikin, 1904 (Box 63, Folder 2)
    - Smith College class of 1908 riding in wagon, 1908 (Box 63)
    - Kenyon with others in Mexico City, circa 1909-10 (Box 63)
    - Various Kenyons and Kinneys in Mexico City, circa 1909-10 (Box 63)
    - Kilmarnock Cross from three different angles, n.d. (Box 63)
    - Kenyon as a young girl, n.d. (Box 63)
  - Personal, 1920s-1972, n.d.
    - Kenyon with Katherine Wilby Berna on porch at Lakeville, CT, circa 1920 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Kenyon with Katherine Wilby Berna, Mary Berna, and William Kenyon Sr. in Lakeville, CT, 1920 (Box 63)
    - Canadian Rockies, 1921 (Box 63)
    - Chilmark, circa 1920s (Box 63)
    - Kenyon with Houston Kenyon and "Figgie" Wilby in front of "Ducksnolan," circa 1930s (Box 63)
    - Thanksgiving at Theodore Kenyon's house, circa 1938-39 (Box 63)
    - Winifred Pitkin at Santiago Tuxtla, 1957 (Box 63)
    - Kenyon and others, 1961-65 (Box 63)
    - Kenyon and others at Chilmark, 1968 (Box 63)
    - Kenyon and Theodore Kenyon, 1968 (Box 63)
    - Kenyon and her secretary Mrs. Elsie Simons, 1971 (Box 63, Folder 3)
    - Kenyon next to green station wagon, 1971 (Box 63)
    - Kenyon seated next to unidentified woman, n.d. (Box 63)
    - Windy Gates estate at Martha's Vineyard, n.d. (Box 63)
    - Cordelia Fuller as a child, n.d. (Box 63)
    - Unidentified man steering boat, n.d. (Box 63)
    - Ted, Jonathan, David and Jim Kenyon, n.d. (Box 63)
    - Andy Jameson, n.d. (Box 63)
    - R.N. Kenyon, Minnie Kenyon and William Kenyon on conveyor belt, n.d. (Box 63)
    - L.V. Pulsifer's home, Houghton Farm, n.d. (Box 63)
    - Christmas photographs
      - Fuller children on camelback, n.d. (Box 63)
      - Jessica and Alison Hopfield, n.d. (Box 63)
      - Pete, Charlie, John, Dave and Ellen Fisher, n.d. (Box 63)
      - Karraker children, n.d. (Box 63)
      - Fuller children in front of brick wall, n.d. (Box 63)
      - Fuller children leaning against tree, n.d. (Box 63)
      - Son of Helen and Michael Brown, n.d.
        - Furman children, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 3)
        - Carrie Chapman Catt, n.d. (Box 63)
    - Kenyon alone, 1920s-70s
      - Kenyon headshot and with vase, circa 1920s (Box 63, Folder 4)
      - Kenyon when she joined New York Bar Association, circa 1936 (Box 63)
      - Kenyon in judge robe, 1939 (Box 63)
      - Kenyon's campaign photograph, 1939 (Box 63)
      - Kenyon in glasses, 1939 (Box 63)
      - Geneva, 1939 (Box 63)
      - Kenyon in hat, 1939 (Box 63)
      - Kenyon (perhaps on her way to Sweden), 1940 (Box 63)
      - Kenyon, 1940 [1 8x10, 1 4x6] (Box 63)
      - Kenyon, 1948 (Box 63)
      - Drawing of Kenyon for "Spotlight" in Chelsea News, 1963 (Box 63)
      - Kenyon in white blouse with enormous sleeves, 1970? (Box 63)
    - Kenyon alone, n.d.
      - Drawing of Kenyon by Gynla (?) Fikey, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 5)
      - Kenyon passport photo, n.d. (Box 63)
      - Kenyon at desk, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 5)
      - Kenyon (head shot), n.d. (Box 63)
      - Kenyon in polka-dot dress, n.d. (Box 63)
      - Kenyon with telephone, n.d. (Box 63)
      - Kenyon, n.d. (Box 63)
      - Kenyon writing at desk, n.d. (Box 63)
      - Kenyon in floral dress (3 poses), n.d. (Box 63)
      - Kenyon wearing long necklace, n.d. (Box 63)
      - Kenyon in front of law books, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 5)
      - Kenyon in hat with bow and fur collar, n.d. (Box 63)
      - Kenyon with book, n.d. (Box 63)
  - Professional
    - United Nations work, 1948-49, n.d.
      - Kenyon with A. Hamid Ali, 1948 (Box 63, Folder 6)
      - Kenyon with women standing on stone ruin, probably in Beirut, 1949 (Box 63)
      - Kenyon at Interlaken, n.d. (Box 63)
      - Kenyon seated at table with unidentified women, n.d. (Box 63)
      - Kenyon and two unidentified women before American flag, n.d. (Box 63, Folder 6)
      - Kenyon with unidentified woman in head scarf, n.d. (Box 63)
      - Kenyon with four unidentified women, official U.N. photograph, n.d. (Box 63)
    - McCarthy hearings, March 1950
      - Kenyon at home with political cartoons, 1950 (Box 64, Folder 1)
      - Kenyon testifying before Senate Foreign Relations Committee, 1950 (Box 64)
    - Honorary, n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon receiving book States' Laws on Race and Color, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 2)
      - Kenyon and two others in academic robes, n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon and four others in academic robes in front of books, n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon and four others in academic robes outdoors (probably at Smith College), n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon and others standing around a table, n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon shaking hands with an unidentified woman, n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon receiving academic recognition, n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon speaking at Hotel New Yorker, n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon and others on stage in academic robes, n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon receiving academic hood, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 2)
      - Kenyon and unidentified man standing under large portrait of Franklin D. Roosevelt, n.d. (Box 64)
    - Professional groups, 1938-70, n.d.
      - Kenyon at Palais de Nations in Geneva, 1938 (Box 64, Folder 3)
      - Kenyon with Fiorello LaGuardia and others, c. 1940s (Box 64)
      - Kenyon with Eleanor Roosevelt and others, c. 1940s (Box 64)
      - Kenyon and Otis Wiese, editor-in-chief of McCall's Magazine, 1947 (Box 64)
      - Kenyon and Axel Gjores (of Sweden), 1948 (Box 64)
      - Kenyon and Madihael Atheri, Mayda Haidary-Mahmoud, and Adiba Ibrahim Rufat (all of Iraq), 1949 (Box 64)
      - Kenyon and others on "Meet the Press," 1970 (Box 64, Folder 4)
      - Speech at Menorah Temple, 1950 (Box 64)
      - Kenyon with unidentified people, circa 1950 (Box 64)
      - Kenyon and others at her 80th birthday dinner, 1968 (Box 64)
      - Kenyon speaking before PTA, 1970 (Box 64)
      - Kenyon with A. Philip Randolph, n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon at unidentified event, n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon and others at Waldorf Astoria, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 5)
      - Kenyon and others in academic robes, n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon and others, n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon and others (perhaps American delegation to Chile), n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon and Fanny Hurst, n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon and Cornelia Otis Skinner, n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon with Cornelia Otis Skinner and others, n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon and a group of unidentified women, n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon and others at an unidentified celebration, n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon and others (perhaps U.N. Commission on the Status of Women), n.d. (Box 64, Folder 6)
      - Kenyon at banquet with Eleanor Roosevelt and others, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 7)
      - Kenyon and an unidentified group of women, n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon and three unidentified men, n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon and an unidentified group of women, n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon at unidentified party, n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon with unidentified people, n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon with three unidentified people, n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon and two unidentified men, n.d. (Box 64, Folder 7)
      - Kenyon and others, n.d. (Box 64)
      - Kenyon and others, n.d. (Box 64)
  - Photo Album: Kenyon's trip to Europe; Kenyon, Stanwood and Wilby families, c. 1900-10 (Box 64)
    [SEE SERIES X. OVERSIZE MATERIAL]
- SERIES IX. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIAL (1948-1998)
  - 80th birthday greeting for Kenyon from Jacob Karl in Feb 1968: 3 3/4" reel- to-reel tape, [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL-Tributes and testimonials] (Box 65)
  - Dorothy Kenyon Testimonial Dinner, 22 Feb, 1968: 7" reel-to-reel tape, [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL-Tributes and testimonials] (Box 65)
  - DK interview with Jacqueline Van Voris for Smith Centennial Study, 14 Jun, 1971: cassette tape, [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL-Interviews] (Box 65)
  - Miscellaneous events including interview with DK on 22 Feb, 1968, Roger Baldwin's message to DK on her 80th birthday, charges by McCarthy, DK's response to Tydings Committee, 1950: cassette tape, [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL-Tributes and testimonials] (Box 65)
  - Recorded interview (on 16" LP) with Kenyon as U.S. delegate to UN Commission on the Status of Women and Ruth Bryan Rhode, former U.S. Minister to Denmark with Dorothy Lewis, Coordinator, Women's Broadcasts, U.N., n.d., [see SERIES X. OVERSIZE MATERIAL; SEE also SERIES VI. ACTIVITIES AND ORGANIZATIONS-United Nations Commission on the Status of Women] (Box 65)
  - Recorded interview (on audio cassette) of Frances Berna Knight by Louise Wilby Knight about Kenyon family, Sarasota, Florida, 29 December 1997. (Box 65)
  - Recorded interview (on 2 audio cassettes) of Edward Tipton "Tippy" Kenyon (DK's nephew) by Louise Wilby Knight, Chilmark, Massachusetts, 6 October 1998 (Box 65)
- SERIES X. OVERSIZE MATERIAL (1938-1950)
  - Certificate of admission to practice before Supreme Court, 1938 (Box 66)
  - Photograph of luncheon in honor of Kerstin Hesselgren, member of Swedish Parliament and of League of Nations Committee on the Legal Status of Women, Hotel Delmonico, July 27, 1938 (Box 66)
  - Certificate of appointment to United Nations Commission on the Status of Women, 1946 [signed by Harry Truman and Dean Acheson] (Box 66)
  - Certificate of appointment to United Nations Commission on the Status of Women, 1947 [signed by Harry Truman] (Box 66)
  - Smith College honorary degree, L.D., 1948 (Box 66)
  - Cartoon by Herblock re: McCarthy's charges against DK (framed), 1950 (Box 66)
  - Recorded interview (on 16" LP) with DK as U.S. delegate to UN Commission on the Status of Women and Ruth Bryan Rhode, Former U.S. Minister to Denmark with Dorothy Lewis, Coordinator, Women's Broadcasts, U.N., n.d. (Box 66)
  - Bridal book of William H. Kenyon and Maria Stanwood, 1887 (Box 67)
  - Index card file created by Mildred Adams Kenyon (Box 68)
  - Photo Album: Kenyon's trip to Europe; Kenyon, Stanwood and Wilby families, circa 1900-10 (Box 69)
  - Campaign poster, 1939 (Map-case Flat file)
- BOOKS FROM KENYON'S LIBRARY (on shelf)
  - Buckley, William F. and L. Brent Bozell. McCarthy and His Enemies: The Record and its Meaning. Chicago: Henry Regnery Co., 1954
  - Dilling, Elizabeth. The Red Network: A "Who's Who" and Handbook of Radicalism for Patriots. Chicago: published by author, 1934. [Inscription inside cover reads: "To Rose Schneiderman whose forthright championship of the 'underdog' has made her a target of the fleas. Affectionately, Lillian."]
  - Fuess, Claude Moore. Stanley King of Amherst. New York: Columbia University Press, 1955
  - Hapgood, Norman ed. Professional Patriots. New York: Albert and Charles Boni, 1927
  - Kenyon, Dorothy. Married Woman's Bill of Rights. New York: Liveright Publishing Corporation, 1943
  - Markmann, Charles Lam. The Noblest Cry: A History of the ACLU. New York: St. Martins Press, 1965
  - Park, Maud Wood. Front Door Lobby. Boston: Beacon Press, 1960